<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<genes>
	<gene refSeqStatus="reviewed" gi="596">
		<name assignedBy="HGNC">B-cell CLL / lymphoma 2</name>
		<symbol assignedBy="HGNC">BCL2</symbol>
		<organism ncbiTaxId="9606"/>
		<aliases>
			<symbol>BCL-2</symbol>
			<symbol>PPP1R50</symbol>
		</aliases>
		<summary>This gene encodes an integral outer mitochondrial membrane protein that blocks the apoptotic death of some cells such as lymphocytes. Constitutive expression of <symbol>BCL2</symbol>, such as in the case of translocation of <symbol>BCL2</symbol> to Ig heavy chain locus, is thought to be the cause of follicular lymphoma. Two transcript variants, produced by alternate splicing, differ in their C-terminal ends.</summary>
	</gene>
	<gene refSeqStatus="reviewed" gi="55245">
		<name assignedBy="HGNC">UQCC ubiquinol-cytochrome c reductase complex chaperone</name>
		<symbol assignedBy="HGNC">UQCC</symbol>
		<organism ncbiTaxId="9606"/>
	</gene>
	<gene refSeqStatus="reviewed" gi="8091">
		<name>HMGA2 high mobility group AT-hook 2</name>
		<symbol assignedBy="HGNC">HMGA2</symbol>
		<organism ncbiTaxId="9606"/>
		<aliases>
			<symbol>BABL</symbol>
			<symbol>LIPO</symbol>
			<symbol>HMGIC</symbol>
			<symbol>HMGI-C</symbol>
			<symbol>STQTL9</symbol>
		</aliases>
		<summary>This gene encodes a protein that belongs to the non-histone chromosomal high mobility group (HMG) protein family. HMG proteins function as architectural factors and are essential components of the enhancesome. This protein contains structural DNA-binding domains and may act as a transcriptional regulating factor. Identification of the deletion, amplification, and rearrangement of this gene that are associated with myxoid liposarcoma suggests a role in adipogenesis and mesenchymal differentiation. A gene knock out study of the mouse counterpart demonstrated that this gene is involved in diet-induced obesity. Alternate transcriptional splice variants, encoding different isoforms, have been characterized. </summary>
	</gene>
	<gene refSeqStatus="reviewed" gi="12365">
		<name assignedBy="HGNC">Casp14 caspase 14</name>
		<symbol assignedBy="HGNC">Casp14provided </symbol>
		<organism ncbiTaxId="10090"/>
		<aliases>
			<symbol>MICE</symbol>
			<symbol>mini-ICE</symbol>
			<symbol>MGC123948</symbol>
		</aliases>
	</gene>
</genes>
